Noah Manion

noah.manion@gmail.com https://noahs.website



3615 South Emerald Ave Chicago, IL 60609 T 412.417.9263

Profile

I'm an experienced growth marketer with a knack for acquisition, funnel optimization, and product development. I've worked on projects with large paid acquisition programs, product-market fit tests with small budgets and provided go to market plans for projects of all sizes. I'm very analytical and believe that strong data infrastructure & a process for building, testing & iterating are the keys to product growth.

Experience

Director of Growth, LandscapeHub - Feb 2019 - Oct 2019

- Launched Lead Generation Campaign focused on bringing qualified buyer leads through Facebook, Google & LinkedIn. Reduced CPL by 45% over four months.
- Created a system of Growth and BI dashboards for easier investor and board communication.
- Created and executed A/B tests using Google Optimize
- Built, Tested & Iterated upon landing pages experimenting with page copy, layout, lead form length & unique selling propositions. Used CSS & JavaScript to create multi step forms & wizards. Increased conversion rate by 400%.
- Created system to plan, track and report on growth experiments, with several tests increasing new user activation by >75%
- Set up sales enablement system using HubSpot, combined internal data to HubSpot properties & custom events to marry data generated by Hubspot with live web app user data.
- Ad hoc SQL query creation

Growth Manager, Digital Intent & Founder Equity Fund - Aug 2015 - Feb 2019

- Validated product-market fit for several clients by planning and executing marketing MVP smoke tests.
- Growth & Analytics strategy for Eat Purely, a Founder Equity Fund investment, to activate leads, resurrect churned customers & develop new strategies to increase basket size and reorder rate.
- Developed and executed on user resurrection & referral campaigns for Eat Purely to increase weekly sales by 20%
- Developed go to market growth strategy for, S'more, a monetized lock screen app. Achieved 360,000 downloads and 45,000 DAUs in 11 months with a blended cost of \$2.50/ user.
- Created & updated product health & BI dashboards (and underlying BigQuery data warehouse) to monitor feature usage & adoption and uncover growth opportunities.
- Lead product strategy to increase activation, retention & referral metrics for S'more through user research and A/B testing.
- Set up a robust user support & feedback system to respond to over 1000 requests/day and transform them into actionable product insights.
- Build & test numerous landing pages & acquisition strategies, messaging & tactics including creating interactive quizzes. Set up event tracking tags both by hand and with a tag manager
- Worked to develop a B2B sales & go to market strategy to put luxury homegoods products in stores
- Worked to find product-market fit & initial traction for a monthly box subscription service

• Lead conversion rate optimization & assist on B2B lead nurturing project for an outsourced accounting firm

SEM Specialist, Brad's Deals – Aug 2014 - Aug 2015

- Manage a monthly paid customer acquisition spend of at least \$750,000
- Forecasted channel spend by modeling payback for acquired customers.
- Optimized bid strategy for paid marketing campaigns by weighing historical ROI, click & conversion rates to calculate a bid strategy for various demographic and interest targets.
- Created a paid acquisition strategy that reduced CPA by 40-50%
- Perform multivariate testing on all aspects of the customer acquisition process
- Create and manage performance dashboards
- Automated campaign monitoring through Google Apps Scripts to manage bidding and

Technical Marketing Instructor, Startup Institute – September 2014-November 2015, Oct 2015-Present

• Taught courses on SQL, Wordpress, Digital Analytics, Paid Marketing & Conversion Rate Optimization

Freelance Marketing Consultant - May 2014-Dec 2014, Oct 2015-Present

- Create and deliver reports and dashboards on customer and marketing analytics
- Manage SEM & Paid Social campaigns for a variety of clients
- Audit websites/apps to increase create SEO, content marketing & funnel optimization strategies.

Database Coordinator, CommuterLink – Oct 2007 - Jul 2013

- Analyzed application usage and new user registrations to identify changing travel patterns and target business development efforts
- Prepared business development plans based on spatial analysis of public open data on parking availability, traffic levels and past client experiences
- Oversaw development of a CMS system for the application to extend the software's use to corporate partners.

Education

Eugene Lang College (New School University) – BA Liberal Arts; 2009 Startup Institute – Technical Marketing; 2014

Skills

Google Ads, Facebook Ads, LinkedIn Ads, Twitter Ads, Google Tag Manager, Segment, Google Analytics, Google Firebase, Google Big Query, Landing Pages, Unbounce, Wordpress, Jekyll, Ghost, HubSpot, Mixpanel, MailChimp, MailJet, Sendy, Digital Analytics, Adobe CS, Airtable, Go to Market, Consumer Insights, User Research, Product Management, HTML, CSS, JavaScript

References

Available Upon Request